# **PERSONAL INFORMATION**

Name: Elizabeth Makokha Anangwe

Registered clinical officer /Health systems management officer

Email: Makokha 1988@gmail.com

Address: P.O Box 217- 50102 Mumias

Phone: +254710309454

LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/elizabeth-anangwe-a5b16b165">https://www.linkedin.com/in/elizabeth-anangwe-a5b16b165</a>

## **CAREER SUMMARY**

An enthusiastic and compassionate clinical officer with 10 years of experience in the medical field from the Kenya Medical Training College, Nakuru Campus I also hold a degree in Health Systems Management from Mount Kenya University where I achieved second class honours upper division. I possess incomparable knowledge of the clinical practices and clinical research work, professional standards of clinical methods and a track record of maintaining confidentiality and protecting sensitive data. Dynamically capable of initiating and discharge planning based on assessed needs, specifically keeping in mind the organizational and departmental safety standards. Currently I work as a research assistant under Ampath and devoted to provide utmost level of ease and care to patients and clients at all times.

# **WORKEXPERIENCE**

Academic Model Providing Access to Healthcare (AMPATH)-Kabula Health Centre; Bungoma County-Research Assistant INTREPiD Study-August 2024 to date.

### **Duties and responsibilities**

• Recruit participants as per study protocol

- Collect and enter data into redcap for all participants
- Perform ultra sound procedure on study enrolled participants
- Maintain contact with study participants and coordinate study visits
- Participate in research related in house meetings and trainings
- Generate research activity reports and share them with the study team
- Ensure all equipment and machines are well maintained in good condition
- Ensure the smooth -running of activities and performing any other duty assigned by the principal investigator
- Ensure that the study office's security is always maintained

Global Network for women's and Children's Health Research-Busia County and Referral Hospital; Busia County-Research Assistant PRIORITY STUDY-September 2023 to July 2024.

## **Duties and Responsibilities**

- Administering informed consent, both verbal and written to all study participants.
- Following the study protocol as expected by the principal investigator, carrying out all the study procedures and filling in of the required Case report forms both in the red cap application on the tablets and hard copies.
- Recruitment, enrolment, randomization and clinical management of mothers in postnatal ward as per the study protocol.
- Administration of the study medication depending on the treatment arm assigned to the mother whether oral iron or iv iron.
- Accompanying the mother home after discharge and getting the correct geo codes for use during the subsequent study visits.
- Making phone calls at different scheduled times to keep track of the study participants while at home.

- Collecting blood samples for haemoglobin levels, malaria Rapid diagnostic test, sickling test and blood ferritin test.
- Attending and participating to the routine hospital continuous medical education.
- Giving health talks to mothers in the antenatal and post-natal wards.
- Performing any other duties assigned by my supervisors.

Global network for Women's and children's health research; Matungu Sub county hospital, Kakamega County: Research Assistant; A PLUS STUDY-January 2020 to August 2023.

### **Duties and Responsibilities**

- Coordinated all the A plus study activities in the cluster (Mumias cluster)
- Administering of informed consent, both verbal and written to all study participants.
- Treatment of sick prenatal and postnatal mothers who were participating in the study.
- Treatment of all under 5 years children whose mothers were enrolled into the study.
- Following the study protocol as expected by the principal investigator, carrying out all the study procedures and filling in of the required forms both in the red cap application on the tablets and hard copies.
- Coordinating and guiding the registry administrator's field activities as per the study protocol.
- Reviewing of women enrolled in the study before delivery on routine basis at the antenatal clinic.
- Recruitment, enrolment, randomization and clinical management of mothers in labour as per the study protocol.
- Routine specimen collection of both the mother and the baby who had signs and symptoms of infections for culture and sensitivity.
- Participating in continuous medical education meetings at the facility, attending various trainings and workshops both in and out of the facility.

• Community mobilization and sensitization in conjunction with the facility Community Health Volunteers (CHVs) and the study registry administrators.

Global Network for Women's and Children's Health Research- Matungu Sub-county hospital, Kakamega County: Research Assistant: ASPIRIN STUDY- January 2016-December 2019.

### **Duties and Responsibilities**

- Coordinated the Aspirin study activities within the Mumias cluster successfully.
- Carried out clinical assessment and treatment of expectant women and new born babies according to the study protocol.
- Coordinated and guided community health workers' field activities as per the study protocol.
- Successfully performed obstetric ultrasound scans on pregnant women after having gone through training by the project and certified by the project radiologist and sonographer.
- Actively participated in the sub-county hospital continuous medical education meetings.
- Conducted follow ups on study medication adherence on all the mothers who were enrolled into the Aspirin study.
- Conducted routine check up on the study participants ranging from blood pressure check-up, Haemoglobin level, and Dry blood sample for Malaria test to the end of the study period.

Riva Health Care Doctors' Plaza (Dr. Joel Ole Kiyapi's Clinic). NakuruCounty-Clinical Officer-January 2013-September 2015.

### **Duties and Responsibilities**

- Offered care and treatment services to the patients in the clinic.
- Completed and maintained relevant patient records and registers as required.
- Maintained good relationship with the management team, patients and the entire doctors' plaza team.
- Assisted in follow up and interpretation of various laboratory and radiological results to the patients.
- Participated in various facility meetings and continuous medical education meetings.

- Attended educational workshop for enhancement for professional and technical knowledge.
- Ensured timely and excellent execution of all duties allocated to and proper management of patients, considering the urgency of their conditions.
- Offered HIV counselling, care, support and referral to the comprehensive care centre.
- Maintained patients' confidentiality

Nanyuki Teaching and Referral Hospital-Laikipia County; Clinical officer intern -January 2012- December 2012

• Under the guidance of the senior clinicians, nurses and medical officers, I did my internship in all the required departments including the inpatient and outpatient.

#### **ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS**

• Bachelor of Science in Health Systems Management

**Mount Kenya University,** Thika, Kiambu County-Kenya. Second class honours, upper division.

• Diploma in Clinical Medicine and Surgery

**Kenya Medical Training College**, Nakuru Campus- Kenya Sept. 2008 - Sept. 2011.

• Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education (KCSE)

Mary Seat of Wisdom Bulimbo Girls High School, Feb 2003-Nov 2006

• Kenya Certificate of primary education

Bululwe Primary School, Butere Sub county –Jan 1997-dec 2005

### OTHER QUALIFICATIONS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

- Competent in computer literacy and programing; use of Microsoft office.
- Holds a certificate of Good clinical practices (CITI PROGRAM), Indiana University.
- Successfully worked with Washington States University as a Research Assistant for 2 weeks
- Achieved certificate in Safe phlebotomy practices- NASCOP.
- Trained in Emergency triage and assessment of the critically ill patient- MEAK.
- Achieved 6-week training in comprehensive care management of HIV/AIDS- CCC, Nanyuki Teaching and Referral Hospital.
- Certificate in Protecting Human Research participants- NIH- office of extramural Research.
- ASPIRIN study training- National Institute of Child Health and Human Development.
- A Plus Study training- National Institute of Child Health and Human Development.
- Active member of Kakamega County Maternal Neonatal and Child Health (MNCH) Civil Society Organization Alliance.
- Experienced Trainer of Trainees (TOT) with the Independent Electoral and Boundaries Commission (IEBC).
- An active Parent Teachers' Association member (PTA) Booker Academy School.
- PRIORITY study training-National Institute of child health and human development

# **REFEREES**

Joseph Kipkoech Kirui

Program Manager- AMPATH

Email: jkirui@ampath.or.ke or josepheddykipkoech@gmail.com or

joseph.kirui@duke.edu Phone: +254720393547

Mr. Kevin Otieno

Data manager- Global network for Women's and Children's Health Research

Email: kevinotee@gmail.com

Phone: +254720707175

Mr. Moses Mukhwana

Area Manager- Lutheran World Federation- Dadaab, Kenya

Email: mosesmukhwana@lutheranworld.org.

Phone: +254720838716